(fanfare playing)
(music ends)
(refrain from\n"My Heart Will Go On" playing)
(sonar pings)
(music continues)
MAN: Thirteen meters.\nYou should see it.
(indistinct radio chatter)
(sonar pings)
Okay, take her up and over the bow rail.
MAN (over radio): Okay, Mir 2,\nwe're going over the bow.
Stay with us.
(sonar pings)
(mechanical whirring)
MAN: Okay, quiet. We're rolling.
Seeing her coming out of the darkness\nlike a ghost ship
still gets me every time.
To see the sad ruin\nof the great ship sitting here
where she landed at 2:30 in the morning\nof April 15, 1912,
after her long fall from the world above.
(snickers) You are so full of shit, boss.
(chuckles)
(mechanical whirring)
(sonar pinging)
MAN: Dive six. Here we are again\non the deck of Titanic,
two and a half miles down,\n3,821 meters.
The pressure outside\nis three and a half tons per square inch.
These windows are nine inches thick,\nand if they go,
it's sayonara in two microseconds.
All right. Enough of that bullshit.
(mechanical whirring)
Just put her down on the roof\nof the officer's quarters like yesterday.
MAN: Sure.
MAN (on radio): Okay, Mir 2. We have\nlanded right on the grand staircase.
You guys set to launch?
Yeah, Brock, launching Dunkin now.
Go, Charlie.
-All right, tether out.\n-Tether out.
MAN (over radio): Okay, Brock,\nwe're dropping down along the hull.
Yeah. Roger that.
Okay. Drop down and go into\nthe first class gangway door.
I want you guys working the "D" deck\nreception area and the dining saloon.
MAN (on radio): Copy that.
-Tether out.\n-Tether out.
Okay, now left. Now left.
I'm coming left.
MAN (over radio):\nSnoop Dog is on the move.
We're headed down the stairwell.
Okay, Lewis, drop down to "B" deck.
Okay. "A" deck.
LEWIS: Give me some rope, Captain.
"B" deck. Get in there, get in there.
BROCK: Watch the doorframe.
Watch the doorframe. Watch it, watch it.
I see it. I got it.
(banging)
(mechanical whirring)
(cracking)
We're good. Just chill, boss.
BROCK: Okay. Make your turn.\nCome around.
LEWIS: Cable out, Captain.
BROCK: Make your turn,\nwatch the wall.
Yeah, Brock, uh, we're at the piano,\nyou copy?
BROCK (over radio): Okay, copy that.
Okay, right there, right there. That's it!
That's it. That's the bedroom door.
I see it. I see it.
We're in!
We're in, baby, we're there!
BROCK: That's Hockley's bed.
That's where the son of a bitch slept.
LEWIS: Oops, somebody left\nthe water running.
Hey, hold it. Hold it. just a second.
Go back to the right.
(mechanical whirring)
That wardrobe door, get closer.
You smelling something, boss?
I want to see what's under it.
LEWIS: Give me my hands, man.
(mechanical whirring)
All right.
Take it easy, it might come apart.
Okay.
Go, go, go. Flip it over,\nflip it over, go.
Keep going. Go, go, go.
Okay, drop it.
Oh, baby, baby, are you seeing this, boss?
It's payday, boys.
(man speaking indistinctly\nover loudspeaker)
(cheering)
Ka-ching!
We did it, Bobby.
LEWIS: We brought it back, baby!\nOh, yeah, who's the best?
Who's the best, baby?
Say it, say it, say it.
You are, Lewis.
-Right here.\n-Bobby, my cigar.
(cheering)
BROCK: Okay, crack her open.
(man speaking indistinctly\nover loudspeaker)
Shit.
No diamond.
You know, boss, this same thing\nhappened to Geraldo
and his career never recovered.
Turn the camera off.
BOBBY: Brock, the partners\nwould like to know how it's going.
Hey, Dave. Barry, hi.
Look, it wasn't in the safe,
but hey, hey, don't worry about it.
There's still plenty\nof places it could be.
Hell, yes! The floor debris in the suite,\nthe mother's room,
purser's safe on "C" deck.
Jimmy Hoffa's briefcase.
BROCK: A dozen other places.
Guys, look, you've just got to trust\nmy instincts.
I know we're close.
We just got to go through\na little process of elimination.
Hang on a second.
Let me see that.
BOBBY: Uh, we might have\nsomething here, guys.
Where's the photograph of the necklace?
We'll call you right back.
Holy...
I'll be goddamned.
TV REPORTER: Treasure hunter Brock Lovett
is best known for finding Spanish gold...
It's okay. I'll feed you in a minute.
TV REPORTER: Now he has chartered\nRussian subs
to reach the most famous shipwreck of all:\nthe Titanic.
He is with us live via satellite
from the research ship Keldysh\nin the North Atlantic.
Hello, Brock.
BROCK: Hello, Tracy.
Of course, everyone knows\nthe familiar stories of Titanic.
You know, the nobility, the band playing\ntill the very end and all that,
but what I'm interested in\nare the untold stories,
the secrets locked\ndeep inside the hull of Titanic.
We're out here using robot technology
to go further into the wreck\nthan anybody's ever done before.
TV REPORTER: Your expedition is at\nthe center of a storm of controversy
over salvage rights and even ethics.
Many are calling you a grave robber.
Well, nobody ever called\nthe recovery of the artifacts
-of King Tut's tomb "grave robbing."\n-What is it?
Turn that up, dear.
I have museum-trained experts\nsent out here making sure
that these relics are preserved\nand cataloged properly.
Take a look at this drawing\nthat we found just today.
A piece of paper that's been underwater\nfor 84 years,
and my team were able\nto preserve it intact.
Should this have remained unseen\nat the bottom of the ocean for eternity?
We can see it and enjoy it...
I'll be goddamned.
(man speaking indistinctly\nover loudspeaker)
BOBBY: Brock!
There's a satellite call for you.
Bobby, we're launching.
You see these submersibles\ngoing in the water?
Trust me, buddy.\nYou want to take this call.
This better be good.
You got to speak up. She's kind of old.
Great.
This is Brock Lovett.\nHow can I help you, Mrs...
Calvert, Rose Calvert.
Mrs. Calvert?
I was just wondering if you had found\nthe Heart of the Ocean yet, Mr. Lovett.
Told you you wanted to take the call.
All right, you have my attention, Rose.
Can you tell us\nwho the woman in the picture is?
Oh, yes.
The woman in the picture is me.
(yelling) She's a goddamn liar!
Some nutcase seeking money or publicity.
God only knows why,\nlike that Russian babe, Anesthesia.
They're inbound!
Rose DeWitt Bukater died on the Titanic\nwhen she was 17, right?
That's right.
If she had lived,\nshe'd be over 100 by now.
101 next month.
Okay, so she's a very old goddamn liar.
Look, I've already done\nthe background on this woman
all the way back to the '20s
when she was working as an actress.
An actress!
There's your first clue, Sherlock!
Her name was Rose Dawson back then.
Then she marries this guy named Calvert.
They move to Cedar Rapids,\nand she punches out a couple of kids.
Now, Calvert's dead,
and from what I hear,\nCedar Rapids is dead.
And everybody who knows about the diamond
is supposed to be dead or on this boat,\nbut she knows.
Doesn't exactly travel light, does she?
Hurry up! Give them a hand!
Mrs. Calvert, I'm Brock Lovett.
Welcome to the Keldysh.
Okay, let's get her inside there.
Hi, Ms. Calvert.
-Hi.\n-Welcome to the Keldysh.
MAN: Hey!
(knocking on door)
ROSE: Yes.
Are your staterooms all right?
Oh, yes. Very nice.
Have you met my granddaughter Lizzie?
She takes care of me.
We met just a few minutes ago.
Remember, Nana, up on deck?
ROSE: There, that's nice.
Have to have my pictures when I travel.
Can I get you anything?
Is there anything you'd like?
Yes.
I would like to see my drawing.
BROCK: Louis XVI wore a fabulous stone
that was called\nthe Blue Diamond of the Crown
which disappeared in 1792,
about the same time old Louis\nlost everything from the neck up.
The theory goes that the crown diamond\nwas chopped, too,
recut into a heart-like shape that became\nknown as "the Heart of the Ocean."
Today, it would be worth\nmore than the Hope Diamond.
It was a dreadful, heavy thing.
I only wore it this once.
You actually think this is you, Nana?
It is me, dear.
Wasn't I a dish?
I tracked it down\nthrough insurance records.
An old claim that was settled\nunder terms of absolute secrecy.
Can you tell me\nwho the claimant was, Rose?
I should imagine someone named Hockley.
BROCK: Nathan Hockley,\nthat's right.
Pittsburgh steel tycoon.
Claim was for a diamond necklace
his son Caledon bought his fianc茅e, you,
a week before he sailed on Titanic.
It was filed right after the sinking,
so the diamond had to have\ngone down with the ship.
You see the date?
"April 14, 1912."
Which means if your grandmother\nis who she says she is,
she was wearing the diamond\nthe day the Titanic sank.
And that makes you my new best friend.
These are some of the things we recovered\nfrom your stateroom.
This was mine.
How extraordinary!
And it looks the same as it did\nthe last time I saw it.
The reflection has changed a bit.
(gasps quietly)
Are you ready to go back to Titanic?
LEWIS: Okay, here we go.
She hits the berg on\nthe starboard side, right?
She kind of bumps along
punching holes like Morse code...\n(makes beeping noise)
...along the side, below the waterline.
Then the forward compartments\nstart to flood.
Now, as the water level rises,
it spills over the watertight bulkheads
which unfortunately don't go\nany higher than "E" deck.
So now as the bow goes down,\nthe stern rises up,
slow at first then faster and faster
until finally, she's got her whole ass\nis sticking up in the air
and that's a big ass.
We're talking 20,000, 30,000 tons, okay?
And the hull's not designed\nto deal with that pressure,
so what happens? (makes cracking sound)
She splits, right down to the keel,
and the stern falls back level.
Then as the bow sinks,\nit pulls the stern vertical
and then finally detaches.
Now, the stern section\njust kind of bobs there like a cork
for a couple of minutes,
floods, and finally goes under\nabout 2:20 a.m.
Two hours and 40 minutes\nafter the collision.
The bow section planes away,
landing about a half a mile away,
going 20, 30 knots\nwhen it hits the ocean floor.
(imitates crashing)
Pretty cool, huh?
Thank you for that fine\nforensic analysis, Mr. Bodine.
Of course, the experience of it\nwas... somewhat different.
Will you share it with us?
(sonar pings in distance)
(orchestral music playing)
(crying)
I'm taking her to rest.
No.
Come on, Nana.
No!
Tape recorder.
Tell us, Rose.
It's been 84 years.
It's okay. Just try to remember anything,\nanything at all.
Do you want to hear this or not,\nMr. Lovett?
It's been 84 years...
and I can still smell the fresh paint.
The china had never been used.
The sheets had never been slept in.
Titanic was called "the Ship of Dreams,"
and it was, it really was.
(people talking indistinctly)
MAN: All third-class passengers\nwith a forward berth
this way, please, this queue. Right here.
It's a big boat, huh?
-Daddy, it's a ship.\n-You're right.
(car horn honking)
I don't see what all the fuss is about.
It doesn't look any bigger\nthan the Mauritania.
but not about Titanic.
You can be blas茅 about some things, Rose,
It's over 100 feet longer than Mauritania
and far more luxurious.
Your daughter is far too difficult\nto impress, Ruth.
(chuckles)
So this is the ship\nthey say is unsinkable.
It is unsinkable.
God himself could not sink this ship.
Sir, you have to check\nyour baggage through the main terminal.
It's round that way, sir.
I put my faith in you, good sir.
Now, kindly see my man.
Oh, yes, sir. My pleasure, sir.\nIf I can do anything at all...
Oh, yes, right.
All the trunks from that car there,
12 from here, and the safe...
to the parlor suite, rooms B-52, 54, 56.
(whistle blowing)
Ladies...
we better hurry.
-My coat?\n-WOMAN: I have it, miss.
MAN: All third-class passengers queue here\nfor health inspection.
All third-class passengers queue here\nfor health inspection.
Chin up.
Welcome aboard, ma'am.
Welcome to Titanic.
ROSE (narrating): It was the\nShip of Dreams to everyone else.
To me, it was a slave ship
taking me back to America in chains.
Outwardly, I was everything\na well-brought-up girl should be.
Inside, I was screaming.
(steam whistle blows loudly)
(speaking Swedish)
Jack, you are pazzo.
You bet everything we have.
When you got nothing,\nyou got nothing to lose.
(speaking Swedish)
Sven?
(clock ticking)
All right, moment of truth.
Somebody's life's about to change.
Fabrizio?
Niente.
Olaf?
Nothing.
Sven?
Uh-oh.
Two pair.
I'm sorry, Fabrizio.
Che "sorry?" Ma vaffanculo!\nYou bet all the money.
I'm sorry, you're not gonna\nsee your mom again for a long time...
'cause we're going to America.
Full house, boys! Woo-hoo!
(cheering)
-Yeah!\n-(screaming)
Dio mio, grazie!
(cursing in Swedish)
-Come on.\n-(speaking Italian)
I'm going home!
(cursing in Swedish)
I'm going home.
I go to America.
MAN: No, mate.
Titanic go to America in five minutes.
Come on. Come on, here.
(Fabrizio speaking Italian)
We're riding in high style now.
We're a couple of regular swells.
We're practically goddamn royalty,\nragazzo mio.
FABRIZIO: You see, it's my destino!
Like I told you, I go to America\nto be milionario.
DRIVER: Whoa, whoa!
Bastardo!
You're pazzo!
Maybe, but I've got the tickets.
Come on, I thought you were fast.
Aspetta!
Whoa! Wait, wait!
Hey, wait.
We're passengers.
Passengers.
Have you been through\nthe inspection queue?
Of course!
Anyway, we don't have any lice.
We're Americans, both of us.
Right, come aboard.
We're the luckiest sons of bitches\nin the world, you know that?
(ship's horn blaring)
Goodbye!
You know somebody?
Of course not. That's not the point.
Goodbye! I'll miss you!
Goodbye!
I will never forget you.
(crowd cheering)
(engines rumbling)
(steamboat honking)
(people shouting goodbyes)
All the way, darling.
360, 360...
Excuse me, ma'am.
360...
Oh, right here.
Hey, how you doing?
Jack.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Jack Dawson. Nice to meet you.
How you doing?
Who says you get top bunk, huh?
(speaking Swedish)
This is your private promenade deck, sir.
Would you be requiring anything?
-Hmm...\n-Excuse me.
WOMAN: This one?
ROSE: No.\nIt had a lot of faces on it.
This is the one.
Would you like all of them out, miss?
Yes. We need a little color\nin this room.
Uh, put it in there, in the wardrobe.
God, not those finger paintings again.
They certainly were a waste of money.
The difference between Cal's taste in art\nand mine is that I have some.
They're fascinating.
Like being inside a dream or something.
There's truth, but no logic.
What's the artist's name?
Something Picasso.
(scoffs) "Something Picasso."
He won't amount to a thing.
He won't, trust me.
Let's put the Degas in the bedroom.
At least they were cheap.
Uh, put it in the wardrobe.
ROSE (narrating): At Cherbourg, a woman\ncame aboard named Margaret Brown.
We all called her Molly.
History would call her\n"The Unsinkable Molly Brown."
Well, I wasn't about to wait\nall day for you, sonny.
Here, you think you can manage?
ROSE (narrating): Her husband had\nstruck gold someplace out West,
and she was what Mother called\n"new money."
By the next afternoon,\nwe were steaming west
from the coast of Ireland
with nothing out ahead of us but ocean.
Take her to sea, Mr. Murdoch.
Let's stretch her legs.
Yes, sir.
All ahead full, Mr. Moody.
Very good, sir.
(bells ringing)
(bell dings)
All ahead full.
MAN (shouting): All ahead full!
Come on, lads. Get moving.
What's the reading?
(hissing)
FOREMAN: All right,\nlet's stoke 'em right up!
We're going full ahead!
Come on. Put you backs into it!
(indistinct chatter)
Twenty-one knots, sir.
Hey, look, look, look! Look, look!
See it?
There's another one. See him?
Look at that one. Look at him jump!
Whoo-hoo!
(wind whistling)
Whoo!
I can see the Statue of Liberty already!
Very small, of course.
I'm the king of the world!
(whooping and yelling)
(whooping)
She's the largest moving object ever made\nby the hand of man in all history.
And our master shipbuilder,\nMr. Andrews here
designed her from the keel plates up.
Well, I may have knocked her together,\nbut the idea was Mr. Ismay's.
He envisioned a steamer
so grand in scale and so luxurious\nin its appointments
that its supremacy\nwould never be challenged.
And here she is...
willed into solid reality.
MAN: Hear, hear.
You know I don't like that, Rose.
She knows.
We'll both have the lamb.
Rare, with very little mint sauce.
Hmm. You like lamb,\nright, sweet pea?
You gonna cut her meat\nfor her, too, there, Cal?
Hey, uh, who thought\nof the name "Titanic"?
Was it you, Bruce?
Well, yes, actually.
I wanted to convey sheer size,
and size means stability,
luxury, and above all,\nstrength.
Do you know of Dr. Freud, Mr. Ismay?
His ideas about the male\npreoccupation with size
might be of particular interest to you.
What's gotten into you?
Excuse me.
I do apologize.
She's a pistol, Cal.
Hope you can handle her.
Well, I may have to start\nminding what she reads from now on,
won't I, Mrs. Brown?
Freud, who is he?
Is he a passenger?
...it turns the propeller
and makes these waves, makes them spin.
It turns and turns...
FABRIZIO: The ship is nice, huh?
Yeah, it's an Irish ship.
Is English, no?
No, it was built in Ireland.\n15,000 Irishmen built this ship.
Solid as a rock.
Big Irish hands.
That's typical.
First-class dogs come down here\nto take a shiite.
Uh, it lets us know where we rank\nin the scheme of things.
Like we could forget?
(Jack chuckles)
I'm Tommy Ryan.
-Jack Dawson.\n-Hello.
-Fabrizio.\n-Hi
Do you make any money with your drawings?
Oh, forget it, boyo.
You'd as like have angels fly out of your\narse as get next to the likes of her.
(laughs)
(talking indistinctly)
ROSE (narrating): I saw my whole life\nas if I'd already lived it,
an endless parade\nof parties and cotillions,
yachts and polo matches,
always the same narrow people,\nthe same mindless chatter.
I felt like I was standing\nat a great precipice
with no one to pull me back,
no one who cared or even noticed.
(panting)
(woman grunts)
(Rose sobbing)
(Rose running and sobbing)
(panting)
(breathing heavily)
Don't do it.
Stay back.
Don't come any closer.
Come on.
Just give me your hand.\nI'll pull you back over.
No! Stay where you are.
I mean it.
I'll let go.
No, you won't.
What do you mean, no, I won't?
Don't presume to tell me\nwhat I will and will not do.
You don't know me.
Well, you would have done it already.
You're distracting me. Go away.
I can't. I'm involved now.
You let go, and I'm gonna have to\njump in there after you.
Don't be absurd.
You'll be killed.
I'm a good swimmer.
The fall alone would kill you.
It would hurt.
I'm not saying it wouldn't.
To tell you the truth,
I'm a lot more concerned\nabout that water being so cold.
How cold?
Freezing.
Maybe a couple degrees over.
You ever, uh,
ever been to Wisconsin?
What?
Well, they have\nsome of the coldest winters around.
I grew up there near Chippewa Falls.
I remember when I was a kid,
me and my father, we went ice fishing\nout on Lake Wissota.
Ice fishing is, you know, where you--
(angrily) I know what ice fishing is!
(scoffs)
Sorry.
You just seem like, you know,\nkind of an indoor girl.
Anyway, I, uh...
I fell through some thin ice,
and I'm telling you,
water that cold, like right down there,
it hits you like a thousand knives\nstabbing you all over your body.
You can't breathe, you can't think...
At least not about anything but the pain.
Which is why I'm not looking forward\nto jumping in there after you.
Like I said...
I don't have a choice.
I guess I'm kind of hoping\nyou'll come back over the rail
and get me off the hook here.
You're crazy.
That's what everybody says, but...
with all due respect, miss,
I'm not the one hanging off\nthe back of a ship here.
Come on.
Come on, give me your hand.
You don't want to do this.
Phew!
I'm Jack Dawson.
(breathing heavily)
Rose DeWitt Bukater.
I'm gonna have to get you\nto write that one down.
(chuckles)
Come on.
(screams)
(grunting)
I got you!
Come on.
Come on!
(screaming)
Help! Please!
Please help me!
Listen, listen to me.
I've got you. I won't let go.
Now pull yourself up. Come on!
(grunts)
Come on. That's right.
You can do it.
I've got you.
What's all this?
(breathing heavily)
You stand back! And don't move an inch!
Fetch the master-at-arms!
Care for a brandy?
CAL: This is completely\nunacceptable!
What made you think that you could
put your hands on my fianc茅e?
Look at me, you filth!
Cal...
What do you think you were doing?
Cal, stop.
It was an accident.
An accident?
It was.
Stupid really.
I was leaning over, and I slipped.
I was leaning far over to see the, uh...
Uh, uh...
The, uh, uh...
-Propellers?\n-Propellers, and I slipped.
And I would have gone overboard,\nbut Mr. Dawson here saved me.
and almost went over himself.
You wanted to see... She wanted to see\nthe propellers.
Like I said, women and machinery\ndo not mix.
Was that the way of it?
Yeah. Yeah, that was pretty much it.
Well, the boy's a hero, then.
Good for you, son. Well done.
So, it's all's well,\nand back to our brandy, eh?
Look at you. You must be freezing.
Let's get you inside.
Uh, perhaps a little something\nfor the boy.
Of course.
Uh, Mr. Lovejoy,\nI think a 20 should do it.
(chuckles) Is that the going rate\nfor saving the woman you love?
Rose is displeased.
What to do?
I know.
Perhaps you could join us\nfor dinner tomorrow evening
to regale our group with your heroic tale.
Sure, count me in.
Good.
Settled then.
This should be interesting.
(whistles)
Can I, uh, bum a smoke?
You'll want to tie those.
It's interesting...
that the young lady slipped so suddenly
and you still had time\nto remove your jacket and your shoes.
(music box playing)
(knocking on door)
(door opens)
I know you've been melancholy.
I don't pretend to know why.
I intended to save this
until the engagement gala next week.
But I thought tonight.
Good gracious.
(chuckles) Perhaps as a reminder\nof my feelings for you.
-Is it a--\n-Diamond? Yes.
Fifty-six carats to be exact.
It was worn by Louis XVI,
and they called it "Le Coeur de la Mer."
BOTH: The Heart of the Ocean.
Yes.
It's overwhelming.
Well, it's for royalty.
We are royalty, Rose.
You know, there's nothing\nI couldn't give you.
There's nothing I'd deny you...
if you would not deny me.
Oh, open your heart to me, Rose.
JACK: Well, I've been on my own\nsince I was 15,
since my folks died.
And I had no brothers or sisters
or close kin in that part of the country.
So I lit on out of there and I haven't\nbeen back since.
You could just call me a tumbleweed\nblowing in the wind.
Well, Rose,
we've walked about a mile\naround this boat deck
and chewed over how great\nthe weather's been and how I grew up,
but I reckon that's not why\nyou came to talk to me, is it?
-Mr. Dawson, I--\n-Jack.
Jack...
I want to thank you for what you did.
Not just for... for pulling me back,
but for your discretion.
You're welcome.
Look, I know what you must be thinking.
Poor little rich girl.
What does she know about misery?
No.
No, that's not what I was thinking.
What I was thinking was\nwhat could have happened to this girl
to make her think she had no way out?
Well, I...
It was everything.
It was my whole world\nand all the people in it,
and the inertia of my life plunging ahead\nand me, powerless to stop it.
God! Look at that thing.
You would've gone straight to the bottom.
Five hundred invitations have gone out.
All of Philadelphia society will be there,
and all the while I feel I'm...
standing in the middle of a crowded room
screaming at the top of my lungs,
and no one even looks up.
Do you love him?
Pardon me?
You're being very rude.
You shouldn't be asking me this.
Well, it's a simple question.
Do you love the guy or not?
This is not a suitable conversation.
Why can't you just answer the question?
(laughs nervously)
This is absurd.
You don't know me and I don't know you,
and we are not having\nthis conversation at all.
You are rude and uncouth and presumptuous,
and I am leaving now.
Jack... Mr. Dawson, it's been a pleasure.
I sought you out to thank you,
and now I have thanked you...
And you've insulted me.
Well, you deserved it.
-Right.\n-Right.
I thought you were leaving.
I am.
You are so annoying.
-(chuckles)\n-Wait.
I don't have to leave.
This is my part of the ship.
You leave.
(chuckles) Well, well, well.
Now who's being rude?
(scoffs)
What is this stupid thing\nyou're carrying around?
So what are you, an artist or something?
Well, these are rather good.
They're, uh...
They're very good, actually.
Jack, this is exquisite work.
Uh, they didn't think too much\nof 'em in old Paree.
Paris?
You do get around for a poor...
Well, uh, uh, a person of limited means.
Go on, a poor guy, you can say it.
Well, well, well.
And these were drawn from life?
Well, that's one\nof the good things about Paris,
lots of girls willing\nto take their clothes off.
You liked this woman.
You used her several times.
Well, she had beautiful hands,\nyou see?
I think you must have had\na love affair with her.
No, no, no, no, no.
Just with her hands.
She was a one-legged prostitute.
See?
(aghast) Oh!
(both chuckle)
Ah, she had a good sense of humor, though.
Oh, and this lady,
she used to sit at this bar every night
wearing every piece of jewelry she owned,
just waiting for her long-lost love.
Called her Madame Bijou.
See how her clothes are all moth-eaten?
Well, you have a gift, Jack.
You do.
You see people.
I see you.
And?
You wouldn't have jumped.
But the purpose of university\nis to find a suitable husband.
Rose has already done that.
Look, here comes that vulgar Brown woman.
Quickly, get up before she sits with us.
Hello, girls.
I was hoping I'd catch you at tea.
We're awfully sorry, you missed it.
The countess and I were just off
to take the air on the boat deck.
What a lovely idea.
I need to catch up on my gossip.
Countess.
So you've not yet lit\nthe last four boilers?
No, I don't see the need.
We are making excellent time.
The press knows the size of Titanic.
Now I want them to marvel at her speed.
We must give them something new to print.
This maiden voyage of Titanic\nmust make headlines.
Mr. Ismay,
I would prefer not to push the engines
until they've been properly run in.
Of course I'm just a passenger.
I leave it to your good offices\nto decide what's best.
But what a glorious end\nto your final crossing
if we were to get into New York\non Tuesday night and surprise them all.
Make the morning papers.
Retire with a bang, eh, E.J.?
Good man.
Well, after that, I worked on\na squid boat in Monterey.
Then I went down to Los Angeles\nto the pier in Santa Monica
and started doing portraits there\nfor ten cents apiece.
Why can't I be like you, Jack?
Just head out for the horizon\nwhenever I feel like it.
Say we'll go there sometime to that pier,
even if we only ever just talk about it.
No, we'll do it.
We'll drink cheap beer.
We'll ride on the roller coaster\ntill we throw up.
Then we'll ride horses on the beach,\nright in the surf.
Now, but you'll have to do it\nlike a real cowboy.
None of that sidesaddle stuff.
You mean, one leg on each side?
Yeah.
Can you show me?
Sure, if you like.
Teach me to ride like a man.
And chew tobacco like a man.
And spit like a man.
What, they didn't teach you that\nin finishing school?
No.
Well, come on, I'll show you.\nLet's do it.
I'll show you how. Come on.
-Jack, no! Jack, no!\n-Oh, come on.
-Wait, Jack.\n-Come on.
No, Jack. I couldn't possibly, Jack.
Watch closely.
Ugh, that's disgusting!
All right, your turn.
That was pitiful!
Come on, you really gotta\nhawk it back, you know?
Get some leverage to it.
Use your arms, arc your neck.
(hawks and spits)
See the range on that thing?
Mm-hmm.
-(Rose hawking)\n-JACK: Okay, go.
(hawks and spits)
Uh, that was better. You gotta work on it.
-Really?\n-Really try and hawk it up
and get some body to it, you know?
You gotta... (snorting)
(swallows)
Mother!
May I introduce Jack Dawson?
Charmed, I'm sure.
ROSE (narrating):\nThe others were gracious and curious
about the man who had saved my life,
but my mother looked at him\nlike an insect,
a dangerous insect\nwhich must be squashed quickly.
Well, Jack, sounds like you're a good man\nto have around in a sticky spot.
(trumpet playing fanfare)
Why do they always insist on announcing\ndinner like a damn cavalry charge?
(laughs)
Shall we go dress, Mother?
See you at dinner, Jack.
Uh, son?
Son!
Do you have the slightest comprehension\nwhat you're doing?
Not really.
Well, you're about to go\ninto the snake pit.
What are you planning to wear?
I figured.
Come on.
I was right.
You and my son\nare just about the same size.
Pretty close.
(whistles)
You shine up like a new penny.
(laughs)
Good evening, sir.
(orchestra playing\n"On the Beautiful Blue Danube")
Good evening.
MAN: Hello.
Do you know that there are\nseveral thousand tons of Hockley steel
in this very ship?
RUTH: Hmm, which part?
CAL: All the right ones, of course.
Then we'll know who to hold accountable\nif there's a problem.
-Where's my daughter?\n-Oh, she'll be along.
There is the Countess.
-Hello, my dear.\n-Good evening, Cal.
CAL: So good to see you.
I saw that in a nickelodeon once
and I always wanted to do it.
(snickers)
RUTH: I'll see you at dinner.
Darling?
Surely you remember Mr. Dawson.
Dawson?
(chuckles)
Well, it's amazing.
You could almost pass for a gentleman.
Almost.
Extraordinary.
RUTH: My dear,\nit's delightful to see you.
What a remarkable voyage this is.\nIt's mad, isn't it?
RUTH: I love your perfume.
There's the Countess of Rothes.
And, um, that's John Jacob Astor,\nthe richest man on the ship.
His little wifey there, Madeleine,\nis my age and in a delicate condition.
See how she's trying to hide it?
Quite the scandal.
Hmm.
And that's Benjamin Guggenheim\nand his mistress Madame Aubert.
Mrs. Guggenheim is at home\nwith the children, of course.
And over here we have Sir Cosmo\nand Lucille Lady Duff-Gordon.
She designs naughty lingerie,\namong her many talents.
Very popular with the royals.
Congratulations, Hockley. She's splendid.
Why, thank you.
Care to escort a lady to dinner?
Certainly.
(chuckling)
Sweet pea? Sweet pea.
Ain't nothin' to it, is there, Jack?
Remember, they love money,
so just pretend like you own a gold mine,\nand you're in the club.
Hey, Astor!
Well, hello, Molly.
Nice to see you.
J.J., Madeleine,
I'd like you to meet Jack Dawson.
-How do you do?\n-Pleasure.
Hello, Jack.
Are you of the Boston Dawsons?
No. The Chippewa Falls Dawsons,\nactually.
Oh, yes.
ROSE (narrating): He must have\nbeen nervous, but he never faltered.
They assumed he was one of them,
heir to a railroad fortune, perhaps.
New money, obviously,\nbut still a member of the club.
Mother, of course,\ncould always be counted upon.
Tell us of the accommodations\nin steerage, Mr. Dawson.
I hear they're quite good on this ship.
The best I've seen, ma'am.
Hardly any rats.
(laughing)
Mr. Dawson is joining us\nfrom the third class.
He was of some assistance
to my fianc茅e last night.
It turns out that Mr. Dawson\nis quite a fine artist.
He was kind enough to show me\nsome of his work today.
Rose and I differ somewhat\nin our definition of fine art.
Not to impugn your work, sir.
(clears throat)
ISMAY: She may be mine on paper,
but in the eyes of God,\nshe belongs to Thomas Andrews.
(whispering) Are these all for me?
Just start from the outside\nand work your way in.
He knows every rivet in her,\ndon't you, Thomas?
ANDREWS: Indeed.
Your ship is a wonder, Mr. Andrews, truly.
Thank you, Rose.
And how do you take your caviar, sir?
No caviar for me, thanks.
Never did like it much.
And where, exactly,\ndo you live, Mr. Dawson?
Well, right now, my address\nis the R.M.S. Titanic.
After that, I'm on God's good humor.
And how is it you have means to travel?
I work my way from place to place,
you know, tramp steamers and such.
But I won my ticket on Titanic here\nat a lucky hand at poker.
A very lucky hand.
All life is a game of luck.
Hmm.
A real man makes his own luck, Archie.
Right, Dawson?
Hmm.
And you find that sort\nof rootless existence appealing, do you?
Well, yes, ma'am, I do.
I mean, got everything I need\nright here with me.
Got air in my lungs\nand a few blank sheets of paper.
I mean, I love waking up in the morning\nnot knowing what's gonna happen,
or who I'm gonna meet,\nwhere I'm gonna wind up.
Just the other night,\nI was sleeping under a bridge,
and now here I am on the grandest ship\nin the world
having champagne with you fine people.
(laughter)
I'll take some more of that.
I figure life's a gift, and I don't intend\non wasting it.
You never know what hand\nyou're going to get dealt next.
You learn to take life as it comes at you.
Here you go, Cal.
To make each day count.
Well said, Jack.
Hear, hear!
To making it count.
ALL: To making it count.
ARCHIE: Bravo.
(Molly laughing)
Mr. Brown had no idea I'd hidden the money\nin the stove.
So he comes home\ndrunk as a pig, celebrating,
and he lights a fire.
(laughing)
(softly) Next, it'll be brandies\nin the smoking room.
Well, join me in a brandy, gentlemen?
-What a good idea!\n-Yes.
Now they retreat into a cloud of smoke
and congratulate each other\non being masters of the universe.
Ladies, thank you for the pleasure\nof your company.
Rose, may I escort you back to the cabin?
No, I'll stay here.
Here you go, Molly.
ARCHIE: Joining us, Dawson?
You don't want to stay out here\nwith the women, do you?
No, thanks.\nI've got to be heading back.
Ah.
Probably best.
It'll be all business and politics,\nthat sort of thing.
Wouldn't interest you.
But, Dawson,
good of you to come.
Jack, must you go?
Time for me to go row\nwith the other slaves.
Good night, Rose.
(clock chiming)
(sighs)
So you want to go to a real party?
(drums pounding, men whooping)
(lively music playing)
Is okay I put my hand here?
Okay.
(speaking Swedish)
What?
(repeats Swedish phrase)
I can't understand you.
(glass shatters)
Hey!
Bravo, bravo!
Thank you.
Pick it up. Come on, lads,\nlet's go!
(music tempo increases)
I'm gonna dance with her now, all right?
Come on.
-What?\n-Come on.
-Come with me.\n-What? Jack... Jack, wait!
(music tempo increases)
I can't do this.
We're gonna have to\nget a little bit closer.
Like this.
You're still my best girl, Cora.
I don't know the steps.
Neither do I. Just go with it.
Don't think.
(laughing)
(Rose squealing with delight)
Wait, Jack, Jack! Wait! Stop, Jack!
(vocalizing)
(dancers whooping)
Wait!
Hey!
Woo-hoo!
JACK: Yeah!
Jack, no!
(yelling)
(squeals)
(giggling)
(Jack yelling)
...on the jurisdiction of the Sherman Act,
so my lawyers will argue.
That's what Rockefeller said,
but the Supreme Court\nis not swallowing it.
(men shouting and cheering)
(lively music playing)
What?
You think a first-class girl can't drink?
(chuckles)
(screams)
Get out of here.
You all right?
(laughing)
(grunts)
-ROSE: I'm fine.\n-(growls)
Two out of three, two out of three.
So...
you think you're big, tough men?
Let's see you do this.
Hold this for me, Jack.
Hold it up.
Ow!
(laughing)
Jesus, Mary and Joseph!
You all right?
I haven't done that in years.
"Drowsy Maggie," lads. Give her a holly!\nLet's go!
Ho!
Coffee, sir?
I had hoped you would\ncome to me last night.
I was tired.
Your exertions below decks\nwere no doubt exhausting.
I see you had that undertaker\nof a manservant follow me.
How typical.
You will never behave\nlike that again, Rose.
Do you understand?
I'm not a foreman in one of your mills\nthat you can command.
I'm your fianc茅e.
My fianc茅e?
(shouts) My fianc茅e!
Yes, you are, and my wife!
My wife in practice if not yet by law,\nso you will honor me.
You will honor me the way a wife\nis required to honor a husband
because I will not be\nmade out a fool, Rose.
Is this in any way unclear?
No.
Good.
Excuse me.
(sobbing)
Miss Rose!
-We had a little... accident.\n-That's all right, Miss Rose.
-I'm sorry, Trudy.\n-It's all right.
Let me help you.
It's all right, miss.
(sobbing)
Tea, Trudy.
Yes, ma'am.
You're not to see that boy again.\nDo you understand me?
Rose, I forbid it.
Oh, stop it, Mother.
You'll give yourself a nosebleed.
This is not a game.
Our situation is precarious.
You know the money's gone.
Of course I know it's gone.
You remind me every day.
Your father left us nothing but a legacy\nof bad debts
hidden by a good name.
That name is the only card\nwe have to play.
I don't understand you.
It is a fine match with Hockley.
It will ensure our survival.
How can you put this on my shoulders?
Why are you being so selfish?
I'm being selfish?
Do you want to see me\nworking as a seamstress?
Is that what you want?
To see our fine things sold at auction?
Our memories scattered to the winds?
(sighs)
It's so unfair.
Of course it's unfair.
We're women.
Our choices are never easy.
Hmm?
(people singing\n"Eternal Father, Strong to Save")
Protect them by thy guardian hand
From every peril on the land
O spirit, whom the Father sent
To spread across the firmament
O wind of heaven, by thy might
Save all who dare the eagle's flight
And keep them by thy watchful...
Hello, Mr. Andrews.
Hello, Jack.
Sir...
I just need to talk to somebody\nfor a second.
-Sir, you're not supposed to be in here.\n-Just need to speak to someone.
...fire and foe
Protect them...
I was just here last night.\nYou don't remember me?
No, I'm afraid I don't.
-Now, you're gonna have to turn around.\n-He'll tell you.
I just... I just need...
Mr. Hockley and Mrs. Dewitt Bukater
continue to be appreciative\nof your assistance.
They asked me to, uh,\ngive you this in gratitude.
I don't want your money. Please, I just...
And also to remind you that you hold\na third-class ticket,
and that your presence here\nis no longer appropriate.
Please, I just want\nto speak to Rose for...
Gentlemen, will you please see
that Mr. Dawson gets\nback to where he belongs
and that he stays there?
Yes, sir.
Come along, you.
Oh, hear us when we cry to thee
For those in peril on the sea
RUTH: And why do you have\ntwo steering wheels?
We really only use this near shore.
Excuse me, sir. Another ice warning.
This one's from the Noordam.
Thank you, Sparks.
Oh, not to worry.
Quite normal for this time of year.
In fact, we're speeding up.
I've just ordered the last boilers lit.
MAN: Okay, son, wind it up tight\nlike I showed you.
That's right.
Okay, now, let it go.
-Was good, wasn't it?\n-Quite nice.
That's excellent, son.
ROSE: Mr. Andrews, forgive me.
I did the sum in my head,
and with the number of lifeboats\ntimes the capacity you mentioned,
forgive me, but it seems that there are\nnot enough for everyone aboard.
About half, actually.
Rose, you miss nothing, do you?
In fact, I put in these new type davits
which can take an extra row of boats\ninside this one,
but it was thought by some
that the deck would look too cluttered.
So, I was overruled.
Waste of deck space as it is\non an unsinkable ship.
Sleep soundly, young Rose.
I have built you a good ship,\nstrong and true.
She's all the lifeboat you need.
Just keep heading aft.
The next stop will be the engine room.
Come on.
Jack, this is impossible.
I can't see you.
I need to talk to you.
No, Jack, no.
Jack, I'm engaged.
I'm marrying Cal.
I love Cal.
Rose, you're no picnic.
All right?\nYou're a spoiled little brat, even,
but under that you're the most\namazingly astounding
wonderful girl... woman,
-that I've ever known and...\n-Jack, I...
No, let me try and get this out.
You're, you're a...
I'm not an idiot.
I know how the world works.
I've got ten bucks in my pocket.
I have nothing to offer you,\nand I know that.
I understand,
but I'm too involved now.
You jump, I jump, remember?
I can't turn away without knowing\nyou'll be all right.
That's all that I want.
Well, I'm fine.
I'll be fine, really.
Really?
I don't think so.
They've got you trapped, Rose,
and you're gonna die if you don't\nbreak free, maybe not right away
because you're strong, but...
sooner or later that fire that I love\nabout you, Rose,
that fire is gonna burn out.
It's not up to you to save me, Jack.
You're right.
Only you can do that.
I'm going back.
Leave me alone.
(door closes)
COUNTESS: Tell Lucille about\nthe disaster you had
with the stationer's.
Well, of course, the invitations had to be\nsent back twice.
Oh, my dear!
And the dreadful bridesmaids' gowns,
let me tell you what an odyssey\nthat has been.
Rose decided she wanted lavender.
She knows I detest the color,
so she did it only to spite me.
LUCILLE: If only you'd come to me sooner.
Ruth saw some of my designs\nin La Mode Illustree.
They were for the trousseau
of the Duchess of Marlborough's\nyoungest daughter.
They were quite charming,
but I think you'll agree, my dear,
that together we've created\nsomething of a phoenix from the ashes.
(women laughing)
Hello, Jack.
I changed my mind.
-They said you might be up here...\n-Shh...
Give me your hand.
(refrain from\n"My Heart Will Go On" playing)
Now close your eyes.
Go on.
Step up.
Now hold on to the railing.
Keep your eyes closed, don't peek.
I'm not.
Step up onto the rail.
Hold on.
Keep your eyes closed.
(giggles)
Do you trust me?
I trust you.
All right.
Open your eyes.
(gasps)
I'm flying!
Jack!
(softly) Come, Josephine\nMy flying machine
Going up, she goes, up, she goes...
(indistinct radio chatter)
That was the last time Titanic\never saw daylight.
So we're up to dusk\nthe night of the sinking.
Six hours to go.
Incredible.
There's Smith and he's standing there,
and he's got the iceberg warning\nin his fucking hand,
excuse me, his hand
and he's ordering more speed.
Twenty-six years of experience\nworking against him.
He figures anything big enough\nto sink the ship,
they're gonna see in time to turn,
but the ship's too big\nwith too small a rudder.
Doesn't corner worth a damn.
Everything he knows is wrong.
(laughing) It's quite proper,\nI assure you.
This is the sitting room.
Will this light do?
What?
Don't artists need good light?
(in French accent) That is true,\nbut I'm not used to working
in such horrible conditions.
Monet!
ROSE: Do you know his work?
Of course.
Look at his use of color here.
Isn't he great?
ROSE: I know, it's extraordinary.
Cal insists on carting\nthis hideous thing everywhere.
Should we be expecting him anytime soon?
Not as long as the cigars\nand brandy hold out.
That's nice.
What is it, a sapphire?
A diamond, a very rare diamond.
Phew.
Jack, I want you to draw me\nlike one of your French girls...
wearing this.
All right.
Wearing only this.
The last thing I need
is another picture of me\nlooking like a porcelain doll.
As a paying customer,
I expect to get what I want.
Over, um, the bed... The couch.
Go, lie down.
-Yeah...\n-Tell me when it looks right.
Put your arm back the way it was.
Right.
Put that other arm up, that hand,\nright by your face there.
Now, head down...
Eyes to me, keep 'em on me.
And try to stay still.
(clears throat)
(exhales)
So serious.
I believe you are blushing,\nMr. Big Artiste.
I can't imagine Monsieur Monet blushing.
He does landscapes.
Just relax your face.
Sorry.
No laughing.
(breathes deeply)
("My Heart Will Go On" playing on piano)
My heart was pounding the whole time.
It was the most erotic moment of my life.
Up until then, at least.
So what happened next?
You mean, did we do it?
Sorry, to disappoint you, Mr. Bodine.
Jack was very professional.
(blows)
Thank you.
(Rose laughing)
What you doing?
Will you put this back in the safe for me?
Mm-hmm.
Phew.
Gentlemen, would you excuse me?
None of the stewards have seen her.
This is absurd.
It's a ship. There's only so many places\nshe could be.
Lovejoy, find her.
Clear.
Yes.
I don't think I've ever seen\nsuch a flat calm.
Like a mill pond.
Not a breath of wind.
It will make the bergs harder to see
with no breaking water at the base.
Hmm.
Well, I'm off.
Maintain speed and heading,\nMr. Lightoller.
Yes, sir.
It's getting cold.
You look nice.
(knocking on door)
LOVEJOY: Miss Rose?
My drawings!
(door closes)
Come on!
No, wait, wait! Wait, wait, wait!
Wait, wait, wait!
Go, go! Down, down!
ROSE: Quickly, quickly!
(laughs)
Bye!
Sorry!
(laughing)
It's all right, sir. I've got it.
Pretty tough for a valet, this fella.
Seems more like a cop.
I think he was.
-JACK: Oh, shit!\n-ROSE: Go!
Come on.
No, over here!
Quick!
(boiler blasting)
(shouting) Now what?
(shouts) What?
Hold up!
What're you two doing down here?
You shouldn't be down here!\nIt could be dangerous! Oi!
JACK: Carry on!
Don't mind us, you're doing a great job!
Keep up the good work!
Ah, look what we have here, huh?
(Rose clears throat)
(clears throat)
Thank you.
(honks horn)
Where to, miss?
To the stars.
You nervous?
No.
Put your hands on me, Jack.
CREWMAN: God, it's bloody cold.
You know, I can smell ice, you know,
when it's near.
Bollocks.
But I can, all right!
Did you ever find those binoculars\nfor the lookouts?
Haven't seen them since Southampton.
Well, I'll be on my rounds.
Cheerio.
(breathing heavily)
You're trembling.
Don't worry, I'll be all right.
(breathing heavily)
They ran down there.
Right.
LOVEJOY: Anything missing?
(exclaims)
I've got a better idea.
Gotcha!
(Rose laughing)
(both laughing)
Did you see those guys' faces?
Did you see the...
When the ship docks,
I'm getting off with you.
This is crazy.
I know.
It doesn't make any sense.
That's why I trust it.
(quietly) Oh, yes.
Here, look at this.
Oh, look at that, would you?
They're a bit warmer than we are.
Well, if that's what it takes\nfor us to get warmer, I'd rather not,
if it's all the same to you, all right?
Bugger me!
(alarm bell clanging)
(telephone ringing)
Pick up, you bastards!
(ringing continues)
LOOKOUT: Is there anyone there?
Yes, what do you see?
Iceberg! Right ahead!
Thank you.
Hard to starboard!
CREWMAN: Hard to starboard!
(ringing)
CREWMAN: Turn, turn! Steady!
(bell clangs)
Full astern!
Hard over.
Helm's hard over, sir.
(ringing)
Go, lads! Go!
(men yelling out orders)
Shut all the dampers!
Shut them!
(dampers slamming)
Hold it.
Hold it!
Now, engage the reversing engine!
(engine stops)
(engine restarting)
Why aren't they turning?
Is it hard over?
It is, yes, sir! Hard over!
(softly) Come on, come on, come on.
Turn.
Yes...
It's gonna hit!
Jesus Christ.
(glass tinkling)
(softly) Jesus.
Hard to port!
CREWMAN: Hard to port!
(men screaming)
Get back!
(screaming)
(hissing)
(screams)
(metal doors closing)
Come on, let's go!
Get out the door!\nThey're closing the doors!
Get out!
Get out! Get out!
Get out the door!
Go on!
Go on! Come on, lads!
Go, lads, go!
Get out!
(screams)
(softly) Oh, my God.
That was a close shave, wasn't it?
Smell ice, can you?
Bleeding Christ.
Note the time and enter it in the log.
What was that, Mr. Murdoch?
An iceberg, sir.
I put her hard to starboard
and ran the engines full astern,\nbut it was too close.
I tried to port round it\nbut she hit and the--
Close the watertight doors.
MURDOCH: The doors are closed, sir.
-All stop.\n-Aye, sir.
(ringing)
Find the carpenter.\nGet him to sound the ship.
Yes, sir!
(cursing in Italian)
Come on, let's get the hell out of here!
Come on, hurry up.
Excuse me. Why have the engines stopped?
I felt a shudder.
I shouldn't worry, madam.\nWe've likely thrown a propeller blade.
That's the shudder you felt.
May I bring you anything?
No, thank you.
MAN: So, haven't spotted an iceberg.\nDid you see anything?
I don't see anything now, do you?
If this is the direction\nthe rats are going,
that's good enough for me.
CREWMAN: Please, sir, please.
Everything's under control.
You there.
Sir, there is no emergency.
Yes, there is. I have been robbed.
Get the master-at-arms.
(yells) Now, you moron!
Yes, sir.
(men laughing)
Hey, you're gonna miss the fun.
Did you see what happened?
No, I missed it.
Apparently, it hit over there.
CREWMAN: Boiler room six is flooded\neight feet above the plate,
and the mail hold is worse.
She's all buckled in in the forward hull.
-Can you shore up?\n-Not unless the pumps get ahead.
Have you seen the damage in the mail hold?
No, she's already underwater.
This is bad.
We should tell Mother and Cal.
I think they're very good, sir.
Don't touch anything.
I want the entire room photographed.
ROSE: Just keep holding my hand.
We've been looking for you, miss.
ROSE (sighs): Well, here we go.
Something serious has happened.
Yes, it has.
Indeed. Two things dear to me\nhave disappeared this evening.
Now that one is back,
I have a pretty good idea\nwhere to find the other.
Search him.
Take your coat off, son.
-Now what?\n-Come on then.
Cal, what are you doing?
We're in the middle of an emergency.
What's going on?
Is this it?
That's it.
This is horseshit!
Don't you believe it, Rose.
Don't!
-He couldn't have.\n-Of course he could.
It's easy enough for a professional.
But I was with him the whole time.
This is absurd.
Perhaps he did it while you were putting\nyour clothes back on, dear.
Real slick, Cal.\nRose, they put it in my pocket.
Shut up.
It isn't even your pocket, is it, son?
Property of A.L. Ryerson.
That was reported stolen today.
I just borrowed it.
I was gonna return it.
Oh, an honest thief.\nWe have an honest thief here, do we?
You know I didn't do this, Rose.\nYou know it!
Don't you believe them, Rose.
You know it. You know I didn't do it.
Come on, son, let's go.
You know I didn't do it, Rose. Rose!
Come on. There's a good lad.
Come on, son. There's a good lad.
Come on!
You know I didn't do it!
You know me!
ISMAY: Most unfortunate, Captain.
Water, 14 feet above the keel\nin ten minutes,
in the forepeak,
in all three holds and in boiler room six.
That's right, sir.
When can we get under way, damn it?
That's five compartments.
She can stay afloat
with the first four compartments breached,\nbut not five.
Not five.
As she goes down by the head,
the water will spill\nover the tops of the bulkheads
at "E" deck from one to the next.
Back and back.
There's no stopping it.
The pumps.
-If we opened the doors...\n-The pumps buy you time, but minutes only.
From this moment no matter what we do,
Titanic will founder.
But this ship can't sink.
She's made of iron, sir.
I assure you, she can...
and she will.
It is a mathematical certainty.
How much time?
An hour.
Two at most.
And how many aboard, Mr. Murdoch?
2,200 souls on board, sir.
Well, I believe you may get\nyour headlines, Mr. Ismay.
Oh, it is a little slut, isn't it?
Will you look at me\nwhen I'm talking to you.
(knocking on door)
Mr. Hockley?
Not now! We are busy.
Sir, I've been told to ask you\nto please put on your lifebelts
-and come up to the--\n-I said not now.
I'm sorry to inconvenience you,\nMr. Hockley,
but it's Captain's orders.
Now, please, dress warmly.
It's quite cold out tonight.
Now, may I suggest topcoats and hats.
This is ridiculous.
Not to worry, miss.
I am sure it's just a precaution.
Everybody up!
Lifebelts on!
(men screaming orders)
What? What's he yelling about?
Everybody up! Put your lifebelts on!
What's the ruckus?
Just put your lifebelts on!
CREWMAN: C.Q.D.?
Sir?
That's right. C.Q.D. The distress call.
That's our position.
(sighs)
Tell whoever responds\nthat we're going down by the head,
and need immediate assistance.
Blimey.
Keep lowering!
Make it fast!
Roll back that cover!
Mr. Wilde!
Mr. Wilde, where are the passengers?
They've all gone back inside.
It's too damn cold and noisy for them.
You there!
(blows whistle)
Get down here and help with these lines.
(orchestra playing\n"Alexander's Ragtime Band")
(people talking indistinctly)
Care for a drink, sir?
-CREWMAN: Please put your lifebelts on.\n-Hey, sonny, what's doing?
You got us all trussed up here,
and now we're cooling our heels.
Sorry, ma'am. Let me go and find out.
I don't think anybody knows\nwhat the hell's going on around here.
It's the goddamned English\ndoing everything by the book.
There's no need for language, Mr. Hockley.
Go back and turn\nthe heaters on in our rooms.
I'd like a cup of tea when I return.
Yes, ma'am.
Mr. Andrews.
I saw the iceberg,
and I see it in your eyes.
Please tell me the truth.
The ship will sink.
You're certain?
Yes, in an hour or so.
All this will be at the bottom\nof the Atlantic.
What?
Please, tell only who you must.
I don't want to be responsible\nfor a panic,
and get to a boat quickly, don't wait.
You remember what I told you\nabout the boats?
Yes.
I understand.
Over here, son.
Sir, they need you up in the second-class\npurser's office.
There's a big mob up there.
Go on. I'll keep an eye on him.
Aye, right.
Sir!
Carpathia says they're making 17 knots.
Full steam for them, sir.
She's the only one who's responding?
The only one close, sir.
She says they can be here in four hours.
Four hours?
Thank you, Bride.
My God.
(crewmen yelling out orders)
Sir!
We are swung out and ready, sir.
Hadn't we better get the women\nand children into the boats, sir?
Yes, we...
Sir?
Women and children first.
Yes...
Yes, sir.
LIGHTOLLER (shouting):\nLadies and gentlemen,
your attention, please!
Step this way, please.
That's right.
Come towards me.
Thank you.
Good.
For the time being, I shall require\nonly women and children.
MAN: Right here.
All right, boys, like the Captain said,
nice and cheery so there's no panic.
"Wedding Dance."
(orchestra begins playing)
Lifebelts on!
Here, put your lifebelts on.
Put your lifebelts on.
Here, put your lifebelt on.
Here, come on, here.
(men talking indistinctly)
STEWARD: It isn't time to go up\nto the boats yet.
Please stay calm.
Look, please, make sure\neverybody you've got your lifebelts on
and, gentlemen, allow the women\nand children through to the front.
What are we doing, Mommy?
We're just waiting, dear.
When they're finished putting\nthe first-class people in the boats,
they'll be starting with us\nand we'll want to be all ready, won't we?
(men arguing)
Go and get some help.
Lower away! Left and right together!
Steady!
Both sides together!
Stop! Stop!
(screaming)
Hold the left side!
Right side only! Right side only!
Right side only!
Hold the left side!
Right side down!
Lower away together!
Steady, lads!
(flare explodes)
(passengers gasping)
(crewman shouting orders indistinctly)
You know, I do believe this ship may sink.
I've been asked to give you\nthis small token of our appreciation.
Compliments of Mr. Caledon Hockley.
Come on, sister, you heard the man,\ninto the boat.
Any room for a gentleman, gentlemen?
LIGHTOLLER: Only women at this time, sir.
Will the lifeboats be seated\naccording to class?
I hope they're not too crowded.
Oh, Mother...
Shut up!
Don't you understand?
The water is freezing\nand there aren't enough boats.
Not enough by half.
Half the people on this ship\nare going to die.
Not the better half.
Come on, Ruth, get in the boat.
First-class seats are right up here.
You know, it's a pity\nI didn't keep that drawing.
It'll be worth a lot more by morning.
You unimaginable bastard.
MOLLY: Come on, Rose, darling.\nThere's plenty of room for you.
Come on, Rose.
You're next, darling.
Come in to the boat, Rose.
CAL: Come.
Rose. Get into the boat.
Rose.
Goodbye, Mother.
Rose!
-RUTH: Rose, come back here!\n-Where are you going?
To him?
To be a whore to a gutter rat?
I'd rather be his whore than your wife.
(struggling)
No! I said no!
(hawking)
RUTH (shouting): Rose!\nPlease stop!
LIGHTOLLER: And lower away!
-Rose!\n-And together!
No, wait!
Lower away!
-Rose!\n-Lower together!
Help!
Can anybody hear me?
(banging pipe)
Hello, help me!
Help me!
(banging on pipe)
Can anybody hear me?
Somebody help me, please!
ROSE: Mr. Andrews?
-Steward, check the starboard corridor.\n-Yes, Mr. Andrews.
Madam, please, put on a lifebelt.\nGet to the boat deck immediately.
Lucy, for God's sake,\nput on your lifebelt.
-Set a good example.\n-Yes, sir.
Anyone in here?
Mr. Andrews? Mr. Andrews, thank God.
Where would the master-at-arms\ntake someone under arrest?
What? You have to get\nto a boat right away.
No! I'm doing this with or without\nyour help, sir,
but without will take longer.
Take the elevator to the very bottom.
Go to the left,\ndown the crewmen's passage.
Then go right\nand left again at the stairs.
You'll come to a long corridor.
(sighs) This could be bad.
(water gurgling)
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit!
(struggling)
Excuse me, thank you.
-CREWMAN: The lifts are closed.\n-WOMAN: I do not care...
The lifts are... I'm sorry, miss,\nbut the lifts are closed.
I'm through being polite, goddamn it!
Now take me down!
"E" deck.
Come on.
Come on, come on.
(screams in frustration)
(Rose screams)
I'm going back up!
No!
No, no!
Come back!
I'm going back up.
I'm going back up!
Crew passage...
Crew passage.
(breathing heavily)
Jack?
Rose!
Rose, I'm in here!
-I'm in here.\n-Jack!
I'm in here.
-Jack!\n-Rose!
Jack! Jack!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
That guy Lovejoy put it in my pocket.
I know, I know, I know, I know.
Listen, Rose, you're gonna have to find\na spare key, all right?
Look in that cabinet right there.
It's a little silver one, Rose.
Silver...
These are all brass ones!
Check right here, Rose.
Rose.
How did you find out I didn't do it?
I didn't.
I just realized I already knew.
-Keep looking.\n-Oh.
No key. There's no key!
All right, Rose, listen.
You're gonna have to go find some help.
It'll be all right.
I'll be right back.
(grunting)
I'll just wait here.
Hello, is there anyone here?
Hello?
Is there anybody down here?
We need help! Hello!
Damn it.
Can anybody hear me?
Please, hello!
Hello!
Oh, thank God.
Wait, please, I need your help.
There's a man back here and...
Wait!
Hello?
(loud rumbling)
(breathing rapidly)
(footsteps approaching)
Hello?
Ah, miss, you shouldn't be here, now.
Wait. Please, I need your help.
This way, quickly.
There is a man down here,\nand he is trapped.
Please.
There's no need to panic.
No, I'm not panicking.
You're going the wrong way!
Let go of me, listen!
To hell with you.
Oh!
(ship creaking)
(flare exploding)
(softly) Oh, my God.
(electrical crackling)
(gasping)
(breathing heavily)
(loud rumbling)
Jack!
Rose!
Will this work?
I guess we'll find out.
Come on.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Try a couple practice swings over there.
Good, now try to hit\nthe same mark again, Rose.
You can do it.
Okay, that's enough practice.
Come on, Rose, you can do it.
Listen, just hit it\nreally hard and really fast.
Wait. Open your hands up\na little more.
Like that?
Right.
Listen, Rose, I trust you.
Go!
-(clanging)\n-(gasps)
(screaming and laughing)
You did it!
Come on, let's go.
Oh, shit, this is cold.
Oh, shit!
Shit, shit.
This is the way out.
We have to find another way.\nCome on.
TILLER: Pull.
(orchestra playing)
Pull.
Put your backs into it, pull!
(distant shouting)
Pull!
Now, there's something\nyou don't see every day.
(distant explosion)
(crewman shouting orders)
LIGHTOLLER: There's no room\nfor luggage in this boat.
What's this luggage doing here?
Get rid of it. Get rid of it!\nWe need the room.
Get rid of that!
(crewman giving orders)
(crying)
Keep calm.
No!
Lovejoy.
She's not on the starboard side either.
We're running out of time,
and this strutting martinet\nisn't letting any men on at all.
There's one on the other side\nletting men on.
Well, then that's our play.
We'll need some insurance first.
Come on.
(pounding on door)
This way. All the way down here.
(Jack yelling)
Here. What do you think\nyou're doing?
You'll have to pay for that, you know.
That's White Star Line property.
BOTH: Shut up!
Will you hold the boat a moment?
-I just have to run back to my room--\n-(grunts)
Sit down!
She's the last.
Prepare to lower.
Mr. Lightoller, why are the\nboats being launched half full?
Not now, Mr. Andrews.
There, look, 20 or so\nin a boat built for 65,
and I saw one boat with only 12.\nTwelve!
Well, we weren't sure\nof the weight, Mr. Andrews.
These boats may buckle.
Rubbish.
They were tested in Belfast\nwith the weight of 70 men!
Now, fill these boats, Mr. Lightoller,\nfor God's sake, man!
Please, I need more\nwomen and children, please.
CREWMAN: Get back in there.\nThis is not an exit.
Get back in there. This is not an exit.
You can't keep us locked\nin here like animals.
The ship's bloody sinking!
Bring forward the women!
Unlock the gates.
Women only!
No men!
(shouting)
(shouting) Get back!
Lock the gates!
Get them back from those gates!
Don't touch the gates!
For God's sake, man,\nthere are women and children down here!
Let us up so we can have a chance!
Get back!
-Jack!\n-Tommy!
-Can we get out?\n-It's hopeless that way!
Whatever we do, we've got to do it fast.
Jack!
Fabrizio!
The boats are all gone.
This whole place is flooding.\nWe've gotta get out.
There is niente this way.
All right, let's go this way,\nall right? Come on.
I make my own luck.
So do I.
Come on!
No, come on, let's go this way.
(crying)
(speaking Arabic)
This way.
Just go back to the main stairwell
and everything will be sorted out there.
MAN: Hell, it will.
It will all get sorted out back there.
Go back to the main stairwell.
Open the gate.
Go back down the main stair.
Open the gate right now!
Go back down the main stairwell\nlike I told you.
Goddamn it!
Son of a bitch!
MAN: Open the damn gate!
Open it!
Fabri, Tommy, give me a hand here!
Move aside. Move aside.
Come on, pull!
(shouting) Pull!
Move aside!
Put that down.
One! Two!
-Stop that!\n-Three!
(yelling)
Again!
JACK: Let's go!
-JACK: Let's go, Rose.\n-You can't go up there.
You can't do this!
LIGHTOLLER: Keep order here.
Back, back, back.
(screaming)
Hold on to her!
Pull her in!
Get back, I say,
or I'll shoot you all like dogs.
Keep order here!
Keep order, I say.
Mr. Lowe, man this boat.
LOWE: Right, is everybody\nall right?
Nobody panic.
CREWMAN: Stay back!
We're too late.
There are more boats down the front.
Stay with this one. Murdoch.\nHe seems to be quite practical.
(women screaming)
(screaming)
LOWE: Sit down!
Stay back, you lot.
Stay back!
Stay back, the lot of you!
(gunshots)
It's starting to fall apart.
We don't have much time.
Mr. Murdoch?
Mr. Hockley.
You two, with me, now.
I'm a businessman, as you know,
and I have a business proposition for you.
CREWMAN (shouting):\nEasy now. All together!
Lower away, lower away.
JACK: Come on, Rose.
The boats are gone!
Colonel, are there any boats on that side?
No, miss, but there are a couple of boats\nall the way forward.
This way, I'll lead you.
(playing final chord)
What's the use?
Nobody's listening to us anyway.
Well, they don't listen to us\nat dinner either.
Come on, let's play.
Keep us warm.
"Orpheus."
(playing fast music from\n"Orpheus in the Underworld")
Music to drown by.
Now I know I'm in first class.
Where is everyone?
They're all still aft, sir.
Do we have an understanding\nthen, Mr. Murdoch?
LIGHTOLLER (shouting):\nWill the men please go back?
(people shouting)
(gunshots)
Women and children only!
Get back!
Step back, sir.
Come through, madam.
This way.
Step back, sir.
Let the women through!
You better check the other side.
Go!
LIGHTOLLER: Stand back, sir!
MURDOCH: Any more women\nand children?
Any children?
I found her on the other side.
Waiting for a boat...
with him.
MURDOCH: Any more women\nand children?
They're all aboard, Mr. Murdoch.
Anyone else, then?
-ISMAY: Hop on, sir.\n-Anyone else?
Do hurry. Hurry along.
Stand by the falls.
(softly) Ugh, goddamn it all to hell.
Shit.
Fire!
Sir!
Sir, you can't go through here.
Sir, you can't go through.
Yes, yes, splendid.
Right.
MURDOCH: Prepare to lower!
Ready on the left.
Take them down.
Keep it steady.
Both sides together, steady.
Give her to me.
GIRL: Daddy...
MAN: It'll be fine, darling.\nDon't you worry.
It's goodbye for a little while.
Only for a little while.
There'll be another boat for the daddies.
This boat's for the mummies\nand the children.
You hold Mummy's hand\nand be a good little girl.
I'm not going without you.
No, you have to go... now!
No, Jack.
Get in the boat, Rose.
Yes, get on the boat.
Yes, get on the boat, Rose.
Oh, my God, look at you.
You look a fright.
Here.
Put this on.
Come.
Go on, I'll get the next one.
No, not without you.
JACK: I'll be all right.
Listen, I'll be fine.
I'm a survivor, all right?
Don't worry about me.
Now go on, get on.
I have an arrangement with an officer\non the other side of the ship.
Jack and I can get off safely.
Both of us.
See? Got my own boat to catch.
CAL: Now, hurry.
They're almost full.
Step aboard, miss.
CAL: Come on, hurry.
Step aboard, please.
MAN: Be Daddy's good girl.
Step lightly.
LIGHTOLLER: Keep back, keep back, I say.
Clear the row, please.
Lower away!
(gasping)
LIGHTOLLER: Steady!
Keep going, keep going.
And lower away evenly, lads.
Easy. Lower away.
You're a good liar.
Almost as good as you.
LIGHTOLLER: Easy now, and lower away.
There's no, uh,
there's no arrangement, is there?
No, there is.
Not that you'll benefit much from it.
I always win, Jack,
one way or another.
LIGHTOLLER: Easy. Even, lads.
Keep going, keep going.
(refrain from\n"My Heart Will Go On" playing)
(inaudible)
Rose!
(passengers shouting)
CAL: Stop her!
Rose, what are you doing?
No!
Rose.
You're so stupid.
Why'd you do that, huh?
You're so stupid, Rose.
Why did you do that? Why?
You jump, I jump, right?
Right.
Oh, God, I couldn't go.
I couldn't go, Jack.
It's all right. We'll think of something.
-ROSE: At least I'm with you.\n-We'll think of something.
Come on!
(gunshot)
Come on, move!
Come on.
-(gunshot)\n-(Rose screams)
Move!
Come on, come on, Rose.
Come on.
(gunshot)
Move, come on!
Move, Rose!
(gunshot)
JACK: Go!
(shouts in frustration)
(metal groaning)
I hope you enjoy your time together.
(laughing)
What could possibly be funny?
I put the diamond in the coat.
And I put the coat on her!
Come on.
(dishes clinking)
(child yelling)
(screaming)
We can't leave him.
All right, come on.
(wailing)
(creaking)
(child screaming)
Go back!
(yelling in Czech)
It's the wrong way! Come back.
(Rose and Jack yelling)
Go!
JACK (shouting): Go!
-Jack!\n-Rose!
(Rose grunts)
(groaning)
This way.
Come on.
Give me your hand.
(straining)
Oh, God!
Help!
ROSE: Help!
Wait, sir! Sir, open the gate, please.
-Please.\n-Please.
Help us.
-Please!\n-Please!
Bloody hell.
JACK (yelling): Come on, come on!
-Come on.\n-Go, go!
Jesus.
-Please.\n-Come on!
Hurry.
Come on.
I'm sorry, I dropped the keys.
-Wait! Please!\n-Wait.
Don't leave, please!
Get more help!
I got 'em.
Which one is it, Rose?
The sharp one, try the sharp one.
Hurry, Jack.
Oh, no.
It's stuck.
-Hurry.\n-It's stuck.
Hurry, Jack!
Hurry!
(screaming)
I got it, I got it!
Go! Go, Rose!
Go, go!
Jack!
Jack, come on!
Move, move!
CREWMAN: Keep on rocking.
Get the oars in place.
Get an oar under it.
MURDOCH: Women and children only,\ndamn you.
CREWMAN: Hold it, hold it.
Hold it!
Get these davits cranked in.
Then get the falls hooked up.
MURDOCH: Get back, sir!
Stay back.
CHILD: Help me.
(crying)
MURDOCH: Stay back, I say!
Keep going up.
MURDOCH: Stop pushing!
Stay back!
Will you give us a chance to live,\nyou limey bastard?
I'll shoot any man who tries\nto get past me! Get back!
Bastard!
Get back!
We had a deal, damn you.
Your money can't save you\nany more than it can save me.
Get back.
CREWMAN: Women and children only!
(gunshot)
(passengers screaming)
No, no! No, Tommy.
Bastardo!
Oh, no, oh, no...
Oh, no, Tommy...
No, Will!
(gunshot)
Stand back, damn you.
CREWMAN (shouting):\nGently! Hold it, hold it!
(screaming)
(child crying)
I have a child.
CAL: I have a child.
Clear a path here.
Please, I have a child.
Please, I'm all she has in the world.
Go on.
Step back, step back, I say.
Please.
WOMAN: Here, give her to me.
Give her here.
(child wailing)
There, there.
Wait, wait, wait.
Mr. Andrews.
Oh, Rose.
Won't you even make a try for it?
I'm sorry that I didn't build you\na stronger ship, young Rose.
It's going fast.
We have to move.
Wait.
Good luck to you, Rose.
And to you.
Mr. Guggenheim.
These are for you, Mr. Guggenheim.
No, thank you.
We are dressed in our best\nand are prepared to go down as gentlemen.
But we would like a brandy.
(men shouting)
Capitaine.
Capitaine, where should I go? Please.
CREWMAN: Captain!
Captain, sir.
(orchestra playing)
Right, that's it, then.
Good-bye, Wally, good luck.
-Goodbye, Wally.\n-So long, old chap.
(begins playing "Nearer, My God to Thee")
(orchestra continues playing)
And so they lived\nhappily together for 300 years
in the land of T铆r na n脫g,
land of eternal youth and beauty.
(continues playing\n"Nearer, My God to Thee")
(loud rumbling)
(crewmen and passengers shouting)
There's no time!
Cut those falls.
Cut 'em, cut 'em if you have to.
I need a knife.
CREWMAN: Cut her loose.
Cut those bloody falls.
Here.
(playing last notes of song)
Gentlemen, it has been a privilege\nplaying with you tonight.
(inhales deeply)
(people screaming)
(screaming)
We have to stay on the ship\nas long as possible!
Come on!
JACK: This way.
Over the rail!
Come on, Rose, jump!
Come on!
(screaming)
(gasping)
JACK: I got you.\nJump!
(groaning)
I've got you, miss!
-Jack!\n-Come on!
Get back!
(cables snapping)
(metal groaning)
No! You'll swamp us.
(hysterical shrieking)
Yea, though I walk through the\nvalley of the shadow of death...
You want to walk a little faster through\nthat valley there?
(screaming)
Row!
Together, men!
(screams)
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners now and at the hour\nof our death. Amen.
-Hail Mary, full of grace, the Lord is...\n-This way.
Blessed art thou...
JACK: Come on.
Come on!
(groans)
I saw a new heaven and a new earth
when the first heaven and the first earth\nhad passed away...
(women screaming)
...and there was no more sea.
Ah!
It'll be over soon.
It'll all be over soon.
And he shall dwell with them\nand they shall be his people,
and God himself shall be with them...
Jack...
this is where we first met.
And God shall wipe away\nall the tears from their eyes
and there shall be no more death.
Neither shall there be sorrow or crying.
Neither shall there be any more pain
for the former world has passed away.
(shattering)
Bloody pull faster, and pull!
(screaming)
MAN: Hang on, Miss Trudy!
(crashing and shattering)
(screaming)
(screams)
MAN: Help me!\nPlease, save me!
WOMAN: Help!
JACK: Hold on real tight!
(shrieking in distance)
(woman sobbing)
(people screaming in distance)
God almighty!
CREWMAN: Get those breakers in!\nKeep them in!
(electricity crackling)
(screams)
(panicked screaming)
(ship groaning)
(planks splitting)
(everyone screaming)
We have to move!
Give me your hand, I'll pull you over.
-I can't!\n-Come on, give me your hand!
I've got you.
I won't let go.
Come on, I've got you.
What's happening, Jack?
I don't know, I don't know!
-JACK: Hold on!\n-Jack!
Rose.
MAN: Help me, please,\nsomeone help me, please!
(terrified screaming, thudding)
(screaming)
(panting)
(screams)
WOMAN: Please help! Help!\nHelp! Help!
(woman screaming)
This is it!
ROSE: Oh, God, Jack.\nOh, God!
-Oh, God!\n-Hold on!
Oh, God, oh, God, oh!
The ship is gonna suck us down.
Take a deep breath when I say.
Kick for the surface and keep kicking.
Do not let go of my hand.
We're gonna make it, Rose.
Trust me.
I trust you.
Ready? Ready?
Now!
(inhales deeply)
(screaming)
Jack! Jack!
Jack!
(screaming)
Jack.
Jack!
(gasping)
Jack! Jack!
No!
Jack!
Rose!
Get off her!
-Rose!\n-Jack!
Swim, Rose! I need you to swim!
Keep swimming!
It's so cold!
Swim, Rose!
Come on. Here.
Keep swimming. Come on.
Here, get on it.
Get on top.
(groaning)
Come on, Rose.
(gasping)
(Rose screams)
Stay on it, stay on, Rose.
Jack.
You'll be all right now.
(whistle blowing)
Return the boats!
(both shivering)
(whistle blows)
The boats are coming back for us, Rose.
Hold on just a little bit longer.
CREWMAN: Return the boats!
They had to row away for the suction,
but now they'll be coming back.
WOMAN (crying): Come back!
For God's sake!
Please!
Help us!
WOMAN (shouting): Come back!
For God's sake!
You don't understand.
If we go back, they'll swamp the boat.
They'll pull us right down,\nI'm telling you.
Knock it off. You're scaring me.
Come on, girls, grab an oar, let's go!
CREWMAN: Are you out of your mind?
We're in the middle of the North Atlantic!
Now, do you people want to live\nor do you want to die?
I don't understand a one of you.
What's the matter with you?
It's your men out there!
(crying)
There's plenty of room for more.
And there'll be one less on this boat
if you don't shut that hole in your face!
WOMAN (in distance): Come back!
(whistle blowing,\npeople shouting for help)
MAN: Here, take this one.
LOWE: Now bring in your oars\nover there
and tie these two boats together as well.
Now make sure\nthat's tied up nice and tight.
Right, listen to me, men,\nwe have to go back.
I want to transfer all the women\nfrom this boat into that boat,
right now, as quick as you can, please.
Let's get some space over there.
Move forward and aft.
(scattered moaning)
(shivering)
It's getting quiet.
It's just gonna take 'em\na couple of minutes to get...
the boats organized.
I don't know about you,
but I intend to write\na strongly-worded letter
to the White Star Line about all this.
(scattered moaning in distance)
I love you, Jack.
Don't you do that.
Don't you say your goodbyes.
Not yet, do you understand me?
I'm so cold.
Listen, Rose,
you're gonna get out of here.
(shivering)
You're gonna go on
and you're gonna make lots of babies,
and you're gonna watch them grow.
You're gonna die an old...\nan old lady warm in her bed.
Not here.
Not this night.
Not like this.
Do you understand me?
I can't feel my body.
Winning that ticket, Rose,
was the best thing\nthat ever happened to me.
It brought me to you...
and I'm thankful for that, Rose.
I'm thankful.
(crying)
(shivers) You must... You must...
You must do me this honor.
You must promise me that you'll survive...
that you won't give up...
no matter what happens...
no matter how hopeless...
Promise me now, Rose...
and never let go of that promise.
I promise.
Never let go.
I will never let go, Jack.
(shivering)
I'll never let go.
(kisses)
(both shivering)
CREWMAN: Right ahead, sir.
LOWE: Oars!
Do you see any moving?
No, sir. None moving, sir.
LOWE: Check them.
Bring that oar up here.
Check them, make sure.
These are dead, sir.
Now give way.
Head easy.
Careful with your oars.
Don't hit them.
(shouts) Is there anyone alive out there?
(distant and echoing) Can anyone hear me?
Is there anyone alive out there?
We waited too long.
Well, keep checking them, keep looking!
(shouting)\nIs there anyone alive out there?
Can anyone hear me?
(Rose singing softly and haltingly)
...my flying machine
And it's up she goes
Up she goes...
Come, Josephine...
(Lowe's voice, garbled and echoing)
Jack?
Jack.
Jack, there's a boat.
Jack?
Jack.
Jack!
(faltering) There's a boat, Jack.
Jack?
(refrain from\n"My Heart Will Go On" playing)
(crying softly)
(weakly) Come back.
Come back.
(louder) Come back, come back.
Hello!
Can anyone hear me?
There's nothing here, sir.
Come back.
I'll never let go.
I promise.
(sobbing)
(grunting)
(blowing whistle faintly)
(blowing stronger)
(whistle blowing faintly)
(whistle blowing louder)
Come about!
(blowing whistle loudly)
(whistling reverberates faintly)
Fifteen hundred people went into the sea
when Titanic sank from under us.
There were 20 boats floating nearby
and only one came back.
One.
Six were saved from the water,
myself included.
Six... out of fifteen hundred.
Afterward, the 700 people in the boats
had nothing to do but wait.
Wait to die, wait to live,
wait for an absolution\nthat would never come.
(refrain from\n"My Heart Will Go On" playing)
Oh, sir, I don't think you'll find\nany of your people down here.
It's all steerage.
WOMAN 1: His hair is reddish brown.
Reddish brown, reddish brown\nand a white beard.
WOMAN 2: Isn't there another\npassenger list?
There's no other list.
Perhaps he's on another ship.
We're doing all we can, ma'am.
There's got to be another passenger list!
ROSE (narrating): That's the last time\nI ever saw him.
He married, of course,\nand inherited his millions,
but the crash of '29\nhit his interests hard
and he put a pistol\nin his mouth that year,
or so I read.
Can I take your name please, love?
Dawson.
Rose Dawson.
Thank you.
We never found anything on Jack.
There's no record of him at all.
No, there wouldn't be, would there?
And I've never spoken of him until now.
Not to anyone,
not even your grandfather.
A woman's heart\nis a deep ocean of secrets.
But now you know there was\na man named Jack Dawson
and that he saved me
in every way that a person can be saved.
I don't even have a picture of him.
He exists now only in my memory.
MAN (over radio): Keldysh, Keldysh, Mir 2.\nOn our way to the surface.
BROCK: You know, I was saving this\nfor when I found the diamond.
(man speaking indistinctly over P.A.)
I'm sorry.
Three years, I've thought\nof nothing except Titanic,
but I never got it.
I never let it in.
(refrain from\n"My Heart Will Go On" playing)
(enchanting music playing)
Ah!
("My Heart Will Go On" playing)
Every night in my dreams
I see you, I feel you
That is how I know you go on
Far across the distance
And spaces between us
You have come to show you go on
Near, far
Wherever you are
I believe that the heart does go on
Once more
You open the door
And you're here in my heart
And my heart will go on and on
Love can touch just one time
And last for a lifetime
And never let go till we're gone
Love was when I loved you
One true time I hold to
In my life we'll always go on
Near, far
Wherever you are
I believe that the heart does go on
Once more
You open the door
And you're here in my heart
And my heart will go on and on
You're here
There's nothing I fear
And I know that my heart will go on
We'll stay
Forever this way
You are safe in my heart
And my heart will go on and on
(vocalizing softly)
(song ends)
(uplifting orchestral song playing)